var data = [
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not correct about coils and loops?",
        options: ["they are irregular structures","if the connecting regions are completely irregular, they belong to random coils","they are regular structures","the loops are often characterized by sharp turns or hairpin-like strctures"],
        correct_option: "they are regular structures"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not a form of RNA",
        options: ["tRNA","rRNA","mRNA","qRNA"],
        correct_option: "qRNA"
    },
    {
        question: "Till date we have not succeeded in generating vaccine against HIV because",
        options: ["it has reverse transcriptase","it mutates rapidly","it don't have any protein over its surface","it is intracellular pathogen"],
        correct_option: "it mutates rapidly"
    },
    {
        question: "The key difference between Lamarckism and Darwinism is",
        options: ["genes are made up of DNA not RNA","DNA codes for protein","variations are at random","evolution is abrupt"],
        correct_option: "variations are at random"
    },
    {
        question: "Cyanobacteria out competes the green algae in eutrophic lakes due to organic pollutions because they can",
        options: ["tolerate low oxygen level","tolerate high phosphorus level","fix nitrogen, so it is not limitating for them","low light is required for photosynthesis"],
        correct_option: "fix nitrogen, so it is not limitating for them"
    },
    {
        question: "The most variable stage of cell cycle is",
        options: ["G1","G2","G0","S"],
        correct_option: "G1"
    },
    {
        question: "Based on which of the following enzymes Hydrolysis reactions are catalyzed?",
        options: ["Hydrolase","Oxidoreductase","Isomerase","Ligase"],
        correct_option: "Hydrolase"
    },
    {
        question: "Who deduced the double-helical structure of DNA?",
        options: ["Watson and Francis Crick","Frederick Sanger","Anton van Leeuwenhoek","Mendel"],
        correct_option: "Watson and Francis Crick"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is abundantly found in collagen?",
        options: ["Tryptophan","Alanine","Glycine","Serine"],
        correct_option: "Glycine"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a function of chaperone protein?",
        options: ["It provides a template for how the proteins should fold","It degrades proteins that have folded properly","It degrades proteins that have folded improperly","It rescues proteins that have folded improperly and allowed them to refold properly"],
        correct_option: "It rescues proteins that have folded improperly and allowed them to refold properly"
    },
    {
        question: "The relationship between oxygen concentration and the fraction of binding sites occupied in \n myoglobin can best be described as ________",
        options: ["Linear with a positive slope","Hyperbolic","Parabolic","Linear with a negative slope"],
        correct_option: "Hyperbolic"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following enzyme catalyzes a reaction that introduces reduced nitrogen ito cellular \n metabolism? ",
        options: ["Bacterial dinitrogenase reductase","Phosphatase","Bacterial glutamine synthase","Bacterial dinitrogenase oxidase"],
        correct_option: "Bacterial glutamine synthase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is an example of epimers?",
        options: ["Mannose & Glucose","Glucose & Ribose","Galactose & Mannose","Glucose & Galactose"],
        correct_option: "Glucose & Galactose"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following are important for white blood cell recognition?",
        options: ["Glycoproteins","Glycosaminoglycans","Glycolipids","Proteoglycans"],
        correct_option: "Glycoproteins"
    },
    {
        question: "A codon contains how many nucleotides?",
        options: ["1","2","3","4"],
        correct_option: "3"
    },
    {
        question: "The initiation codon is ____________",
        options: ["AUG","UAA","UAG","UGA"],
        correct_option: "AUG"
    },
    {
        question: "The termination codon is not __________",
        options: ["AUG","UAA","UAG","UGA"],
        correct_option: "AUG"
    },
    {
        question: "How many t-RNAs are required to translate all 61 codons?",
        options: ["31","32","30","29"],
        correct_option: "32"
    },
    {
        question: "The genetic code translated the language of ___________",
        options: ["Proteins into that of RNA","Amino acids into that of RNA","RNA into that of proteins","RNA into that of DNA"],
        correct_option: "RNA into that of proteins"
    },
    {
        question: "What is DNA replication?",
        options: ["Conservative","Non-conservative","Semi-conservative","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Semi-conservative"
    },
    {
        question: "Eukaryotes differ from prokaryote in mechanism of DNA replication due to __________",
        options: ["Use of DNA primer rather than RNA primer","Different enzyme for synthesis of lagging and leading strand","Discontinuous rather than semi-discontinuous replication","Unidirectional rather than semi-discontinuous replication"],
        correct_option: "Discontinuous rather than semi-discontinuous replication"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is true about DNA polymerase?",
        options: ["It can synthesize DNA in the 5’ to 3’ direction","It can synthesize DNA in the 3’ to 5’ direction","It can synthesize mRNA in the 3’ to 5’ direction","It can synthesize mRNA in the 5’ to 3’ direction"],
        correct_option: "It can synthesize DNA in the 5’ to 3’ direction"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following enzymes remove supercoiling in replicating DNA ahead of the replication \n fork?",
        options: ["DNA polymerases","Helicases","Primases","Topoisomerases"],
        correct_option: "Topoisomerases"
    },
    {
        question: "DNA unwinding is done by ____________",
        options: ["Ligase","Helicase","Topoisomerase","Hexonuclease"],
        correct_option: "Helicase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which enzyme used to join bits of DNA?",
        options: ["DNA polymerase","DNA ligase","Endonuclease","Primase"],
        correct_option: "DNA ligase"
    },
    {
        question: "Translation takes place before transcription.",
        options: ["True","False","Both take place at same time","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "False"
    },
    {
        question: "Protein synthesis in bacteria takes place on which of the following organelles?",
        options: ["Endoplasmic Reticulum","Golgi body","Ribosomes","Mitochondria"],
        correct_option: "Ribosomes"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following RNA constitutes 90 percent of the total cellular RNA?",
        options: ["rRNA","tRNA","mRNA","hnRNA"],
        correct_option: "rRNA"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is responsible for the initiation of RNA polymerase activity?",
        options: ["initiation site","promoter region","sigma factor","rho factor"],
        correct_option: "sigma factor"
    },
    {
        question: "The following code codes for which of the amino acid respectively? \n AUG and GUG",
        options: ["Phenylalanine, tyrosine","Methionine, valine","Methionine, alanine","Lysine, valine"],
        correct_option: "Methionine, valine"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these restriction enzymes produce blunt ends?",
        options: ["SaII","EcoRV","XhoI","HindIII"],
        correct_option: "EcoRV"
    },
    {
        question: "Restriction enzymes are named for",
        options: ["the person who discovered","the bacterium they are derived from","the viral DNA that they attack","none of the above"],
        correct_option: "the bacterium they are derived from"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following techniques can be used to determine the defective gene and for developing cancer?",
        options: ["Western blot","Southern blot","Northern blot","Eastern blot"],
        correct_option: "Southern blot"
    },
    {
        question: "In order to insert a foreign gene into a plasmid, both must _____",
        options: ["have identical DNA sequences","originate from the same type of cell","be cut by the same restriction enzyme","be of the same length"],
        correct_option: "be cut by the same restriction enzyme"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following genetic diseases would be amenable to genetic engineering?",
        options: ["Down's syndrome","Muscular dystrophy","Cystic fibrosis","Cri du Chat"],
        correct_option: "Cystic fibrosis"
    },
    {
        question: "X-rays cause",
        options: ["the formation of thymine dimers","ionization of water in the cell","heat","none of the above"],
        correct_option: "ionization of water in the cell"
    },
    {
        question: "Why is golden rice pale yellow in color?",
        options: ["It is rich in chlorophyll a","It is rich in beta-carotene","It is rich in chlorophyll b","It is rich in phycobilins"],
        correct_option: "It is rich in beta-carotene"
    },
    {
        question: "Who developed the chemical techniques to synthesize polynucleotides?",
        options: ["Barbara McClintock","James Watson","Fredrick Sanger","H. Gobind Khorana"],
        correct_option: "H. Gobind Khorana"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following enzymes in bacteria are responsible for restricting the growth of viruses?",
        options: ["restriction endonuclease","topoisomerase","gyrase","protease"],
        correct_option: "restriction endonuclease"
    },
    {
        question: "The first recombinant DNA molecule was synthesized in the year __________",
        options: ["1962","1972","1982","1992"],
        correct_option: "1972"
    },
    {
        question: "Point mutation involves",
        options: ["deletion","insertion","duplication","change in single base pair"],
        correct_option: "change in single base pair"
    },
    {
        question: "Transition type of gene mutation is caused when",
        options: ["GC is replaced by TA","CG is replaced by GC","AT is replaced by CG","AT is replaced by GC"],
        correct_option: "AT is replaced by GC"
    },
    {
        question: "How many kinds of mutation are found in DNA which includes mutation of only one base?",
        options: ["1","2","3","4"],
        correct_option: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "By which process miss-incorporated base can change into a permanent mutation?",
        options: ["Replication","Transcription","Translation","Transposition"],
        correct_option: "Replication"
    },
    {
        question: "In E. coli mismatches are detected by which repair protein?",
        options: ["Mut H","Mut L","Mut S","Mut D"],
        correct_option: "Mut S"
    },
    {
        question: "In a living organism, strong interactions between molecules are formed by a certain type of bond. Which is that?",
        options: ["Hydrogen bond","Covalent bond","Electrostatic interactions","Van der Waals forces"],
        correct_option: "Covalent bond"
    },
    {
        question: "Among all the heat shock proteins, which one is known as chaperonins?",
        options: ["Hsp70","Hsp32","Hsp60","Hsp30"],
        correct_option: "Hsp60"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following name is given to molecular chaperones?",
        options: ["Allosteric protein","Heat shock protein","Denaturation protein","Ribonuclease"],
        correct_option: "Heat shock protein"
    },
    {
        question: "Holoenzyme is made of",
        options: ["Apoenzyme and Zymogen","Apoenzyme and Co-enzyme","Co-enzyme and Prosthetic group","Prosthetic group and Co-factor"],
        correct_option: "Apoenzyme and Co-enzyme"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following organelle is called ‘Suicidal Bag’",
        options: ["Mitochondria","Endoplasmic reticulum","Lysosome","Ribosome"],
        correct_option: "Lysosome"
    },
    {
        question: "Number of iron atoms in one haemoglobin molecule are",
        options: ["1","4","3","8"],
        correct_option: "4"
    },
    {
        question: "In competitive inhibition, inhibitors bears a close structural similarity with the",
        options: ["Co-enzyme","Co-factor","Prosthetic group","Substrate"],
        correct_option: "Substrate"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following forces is favorable for protein folding?",
        options: ["Hydrophobic interactions","Hydrogen bonding","Vander Waals forces","Ionic bonding"],
        correct_option: "Hydrophobic interactions"
    },
    {
        question: "Process of folding does not depend on __________",
        options: ["Concentration of salts","pH","Solute","Solvent"],
        correct_option: "Solute"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is true about ribonucease?",
        options: ["Native state which is catalytically inactive is denatured","Unfolded state is inactive","Renatured ribonuclease is inactive","Renaturation involves reestablishment of the correct disulfide cross links"],
        correct_option: "Native state which is catalytically inactive is denatured"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the length of a motif, in terms of amino acids residues",
        options: ["30- 60","10-20","70-90","1-10"],
        correct_option: "10-20"
    },
    {
        question: "On average, what is the length of a typical domain?",
        options: ["About 100 residues","About 300 residues","About 500 residues","About 900 residues"],
        correct_option: "About 100 residues"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following wrongly describes protein domains?",
        options: ["They are made up of one secondary structure","Defined as independently foldable units","They are stable structures as compared to motifs","They are separated by linker regions"],
        correct_option: "They are made up of one secondary structure"
    },
    {
        question: "In the zinc finger, which residues in this sequence motif form ligands to a zinc ion?",
        options: ["Cysteine and histidine","Cysteine and arginine","Histidine and proline","Histidine and arginine"],
        correct_option: "Cysteine and histidine"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following factors is not responsible for the denaturation of proteins?",
        options: ["Heat","Charge","pH change","Organic solvents"],
        correct_option: "Charge"
    },
    {
        question: "_______is not a classified form of conjugated proteins.",
        options: ["Lipoproteins","Glycoproteins","Metalloproteins","Complete proteins"],
        correct_option: "Complete proteins"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the average molecular weight of an amino acid residue in a protein?",
        options: ["120","110","130","140"],
        correct_option: "110"
    },
    {
        question: "The formation of _____ is determined by ______ interactions, whereas the formation of ____ is \n strongly influenced by ______ interactions.",
        options: ["α-helices, long-range, α-helices, short-range","α-helices, long-range, β-strands, short-range","α-helices, short-range, β-strands, long-range","β-strands, short-range, β-strands, long-range"],
        correct_option: "α-helices, short-range, β-strands, long-range"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue regarding Ab Initio–Based Methods?",
        options: ["This type of method predicts the secondary structure based on a single query sequence","This type of method predicts the secondary structure based on a multiple query sequence","It measures the relative propensity of each amino acid belonging to a certain secondary structure \n element","The propensity scores are derived from known crystal structures"],
        correct_option: "This type of method predicts the secondary structure based on a multiple query sequence"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following does not affect the stability of an α-helix?",
        options: ["Electrostatic repulsion","Bulkiness","Interaction between R groups spaced three residues apart","Occurrence of alanine and glycine residues"],
        correct_option: "Occurrence of alanine and glycine residues"
    },
    {
        question: "β-pleated sheets are the examples of ________",
        options: ["Primary structure","Secondary structure","Tertiary structure","Quaternary structure"],
        correct_option: "Secondary structure"
    },
    {
        question: "Secondary structure is defined by _______",
        options: ["Hydrogen bonding","Van der Waals force","Covalent bonding","Ionic bonding"],
        correct_option: "Hydrogen bonding"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a false statement?",
        options: ["α-Keratin is α helical","Collagen is α helical","Hemoglobin has a quaternary structure","α-Keratin is β pleated structure"],
        correct_option: "α-Keratin is β pleated structure"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following properties is improved by site directed mutagenesis?",
        options: ["Physical property","Chemical property","Kinetic property","Integrity"],
        correct_option: "Kinetic property"
    },
    {
        question: "Which phage is used in oligonucleotide directed mutagenesis?",
        options: ["M13","Cosmid","Phagemid","λ – phage"],
        correct_option: "M13"
    },
    {
        question: "Write down the name of scientist who has discovered the method of site directed mutagenesis?",
        options: ["Bostein Shortle","Craik","Grait","Joller Smith"],
        correct_option: "Joller Smith"
    },
]

export default data;